Tags are a way of identifying game objects in Unity.
タグとは、Unity でゲームオブジェクトを識別するひとつの方法です。
As a name of a single object could identify it,
ひとつのオブジェクトの名前によりオブジェクトを見つけるのと同様に、
it can be useful to set tags also.
タグもまた見つけるために使用すると便利です。
For example you may have an object called Ork or Tank
例えば Ork または Tank と呼ばれるオブジェクトがあるかもしれませんが、
but these could all be tagged Enemy,
これらはすべて Enemy とタグをつけてしまえば
and in your code you could check for any objects
コードの中で Enemy タグのある全てのオブジェクトを
that have the tag Enemy.
見つけることが出来ます。
Likewise a script on an enemy could check for a player character
同様にして Enemy にあるスクリプトは Player キャラクターを見つけるために
by looking for a player tag.
Player タグを使用出来ます。
To assign a tag to an object, select it and use the
オブジェクトにタグを割り当てるには、選択をしたうえで
drop-down menu at the top of the inspector.
インスペクタ上部にあるドロップダウンメニューを使用します。
If the tag you want isn't already present then add a new tag.
もし必要とするタグがすでに存在しない場合、新しいタグを追加します。
You can add a tag by clicking the option at the bottom of the menu
タグを追加するにはメニューの下部にあるオプションをクリックして
and then entering it in the list of tags at the top
Tag Manager の上にあるタグの一覧に
of the tag manager.
入力します。
Once you've done this, return to the object you
完了した後は、タグをつけたい
wish to place the tag on
オブジェクトに戻って
and select it from the drop-down.
ドロップダウンから選択します。
There are a number of functions in code,
コードにはいくつかの関数があり
which will allow you to find objects with tags,
これによりタグつきのオブジェクトを見つけることが出来て
the simplest one of these is GameObject.FindWithTag,
そのもっとも簡単なものが GameObject.FindWithTag です。
which allows you to specify a string with the name
この関数によりタグの名前を
of the tag inside it.
引数に指定することが出来ます。
This script is attached to my enemy object
このスクリプトは Enemy オブジェクトにアタッチされて
and I can use that to find an object with the tag Player.
そして Player タグのついたオブジェクトを見つけるのに使用することが出来ます。
So I'll set my robot to be tagged Player
それでは ロボットのタグを Player として
and when the game starts my enemy is seeking out that
ゲームが開始したとき、Enemy はそのオブジェクトを探して
object and looking at it.
そちらの方向をに顔を向けます。
Likewise you could find multiple objects with the same tag
同様にして、同じタグのある複数のオブジェクトを
by using FindGameObjectWithTag.
FindGameObjectWithTag を使用して見つけることが出来ます。
See the scripting reference for more examples of this.
より多くのサンプルについてはスクリプティング リファレンスを参照して下さい。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)